Justin J Raver

https://www.linkedin.com/in/justinjayrayer/| 208.699.7270 | justinjrayer@gmail.com

SUMMARY

As an individual with a proven track record of dedication, strong work ethic, and determination, I am seeking an internship position to further my studies and abilities as a computer science student. Having worked in team-based environments for the last eight years, I have built on my strong ability to communicate with others, generate unique and interesting solutions, and solve difficult problems.

EDUCATION

Boise State University, School of Engineering

Anticipated Graduation December 2021

Major: B.S. In Computer Science | GPA: 3.5

Honors, Awards and Achievements: College of Engineering Deans List

Related Coursework: Computer Science I, II, III, & IV Java Programming, Data Structures, Algorithms, Database Systems, Systems Programming, Parallel Programming(MPI,OpenMP,CUDA), Intro to Web Development, Agile Development, Version Control(GIT), Microprocessors, Navigating Computer Systems, Calculus I & II, Discrete Mathematics, Probability and Statistics, College Writing and Research, Fundamentals of Communication, Intro to Technical Communication

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rohner Spray Booths; Boise, ID

Web Developer 12/2020-Current

- Designing and developing production management system to manage inventory, contracts, and related bill of materials
- Communicating directly with leadership to gather user stories, develop use cases, and manage product development
- Collaborating with team members to ensure timely delivery of product features, quality assurance, and product release

Boise State University; Boise, ID

Student Learning Assistant

8/2019 - 12/2019

- Improved individuals understanding of introductory programming concepts such as: variables, loops, Booleans, and lists in the python language
- Adapted to unique challenges of teaching programming to a person with visual impairments
- Facilitated communication between the student and professor to ensure all goals were met

The Golf Club at Black Rock; Coeur D' Alene, ID **Golf maintenance Crew Member**

Interpersonal Problem-Solving,

Dependability, Professionalism

2013-2020(Seasonal)

- Worked closely with teams both as a leader and member to achieve daily maintenance tasks
- Learned complex skills quickly and carried out duties in a timely manner
- Communicated with course staff and members to ensure quality guest experiences
- Taught new employee's complex tasks through simple and easy to understand methods

SKILLS

Personal:

ACTIVITIES *Computer:* Java, C, MySQL, Object Oriented

> Programming, Test-Driven *Volunteer:* Coeur D' Alene Special Olympics,

Development(JUnit), Version Control(Git), Ironman Coeur D' Alene

Unix system navigation, Black Box Testing, Member: BSU Computer Science Club, A.I. Club,

North Idaho College Philosophy Club

Exposure to: Python, Django, PHP, CSS, HTML, Javascript, Bootstrap Hobbies: Traveling (Over eight months of travel

in Asia and South America), Outdoors

Communication, Organization, Recreation (Fly-fishing, skiing, and

backpacking)

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Available Upon Request